Guide to the Sam Shepard and Johnny Dark Collection
The Wittliff Collections
- Correspondence, 1972-2011
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., July 20, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 5 p., July 22, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p., July 26, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p., July 28, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, July 29, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 6 p. Envelope Included. 8 photographs and 5 photocopy pages enclosed, July 30, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 1 p. Envelope included. 3 pages from Development of Insight enclosed, July 31, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 1 p. Envelope included, August 2, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 1 p. Envelope included., August 3, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 1 p. Envelope included, August 6, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 6 p. Envelope included, August 6, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 2 p. Envelope included. 24 pages enclosed, August 7, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p., August 9, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 5 p. Envelope included, August 13, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 6 p. Envelope included, August 13, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p., August 15, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 1 p. Envelope included, August 16, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 5 p. Envelope included, August 18, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 5 p. Envelope included, August 20, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p., August 21, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 4 p., August 23, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p., August 25, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 3 p. Envelope included, August 26, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 5 p. Envelope included, August 29, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, August 30, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 1 p. Envelope included, August 31, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 5 p. Envelope included, August 31, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., September 2, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 1 p. Envelope included. 4 photocopy pages from Kerouac/Cassidy letters, September 2, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 5 p. Envelope include, September 7, 2010. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 4 p. Newspaper clippings re: gun violence, 2 photographs, and 2 "sample of 3rd person 'Sam' book.", September 8, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 4 p. Chapter from Dark's "Scarlett book" enclosed, September 10, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 4 p. Envelope included, September 11, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 2 p., December 7, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. [Photocopy] TLS, 1 p., January 27, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., January 30, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard [Photocopy] TLS, 2 p., February 3, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard, [Photocopy] TLS, 4 p., February 6, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. [Photocopy] TLS, 7 p., February 7, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 1 p., February 11, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. [Photocopy] AL, 1 p., March 18, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Twenty-three undated letters from Dark to Shepard (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Dark writings sent to Shepard, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Dialogues, 1984
  Series II: Dialogues is over 200 pages of typed transcripts of conversations that Dark and Shepard recorded in the 1970s and 1980s. Arranged in themed sections by Dark, the conversations cover a wide range of topics including relationships, writing, film, ageing, and friendship.
  - The San Francisco Conversations. Inscribed, "May 14, 1984. For Sam, My best friend and brother. Johnny.", 1978-1983
    Contents
    Titled sections [approximately 1-4 pages each]
    Introduction Themes and Subjects Life Einstein Marilyn Monroe and Hollywood Hugh Hefner and Playboy Howard Hughes Biographys [sic] Harry Truman The Feeling of Places Movies and Plays Overhearing Yourself Gangsters The Moth Neighbors Writing and Imagination Interviews and the Boarding House Presence and Effort Ideas and Projects Resturants [sic] and Neighborhood Eyes and Light Pretending Chicken, Cafes and Loafers The Prospector Play Theatre Form Insults The Hotel L.A. Posessions [sic] Shepard's Plays "Period" Movies Advice Zane Grey Radio Voice Stage Directing Sight Gags and Circuses Reactions to Fear Dennis in the Theatre Casting Teenage Memories The First Girl Julie Harris and the Senator from Baltimore Theatre Sound Sound and the Movies Movie Characters The Right Stuff Fool For Love A Friend Manhatten [sic] Film Production Meeting The Room Possibilities Arnald [sic] and the Vaquaroes [sic] Fag Mailmen and Cursing 4-F Haircuts Folk Singers and Cowboy Stars Neil Cassidy Bird Imitation Living with the Carpenters Ideas for a Film 2 by Truffeut On the Ranch Coach McAdams Zen Mountain Sets and Came Dressing Up Nature Walking the Property – '76 Collaberation [sic] Book Inscription The Pink Panther Lip Syncing Matt Painting Talking Formally Micraphones [sic] in the Movies The Origin and Power of Moving Pictures Possible Origins of Theatre and the Decline of the Form of American Movie Theaters The Death Scene Planning for the Filming of Endgame Singing and Remembering The New Mexico Conversations Relating Historical Events Jokes, Humor and Comedians Woody Allen A Phase Ageing Beginnings Movie Endings Betrayal Movies Conversation Changer An Out of Control Reminisence [sic] A Slapped Down Town On the Road Old Friends at the Lodge Loading the Gun Spelling on the Desert Out on the Desert at Night Having a Mission Omens, Lesson and Elders Remembering In Front of the Bookcase The Old Man Relationships Mid Life Crisis
    Conversations between J. and S. and S's son Jesse who was ten between the ages of 7 and 9, 1977 to 1979 California
    The Rasberry [sic] Story Whale Meat and Grapes Feeling the Salami School Teachers Teasing the Kid
- Photographs, 1969-2010
  Series III: Photographs is comprised of photographs collected by Dark. Many are mounted onto notebook pages with annotations in Dark's hand. These photographs provide a glimpse into the private lives of the men. The bulk of the photos are of Shepard and Dark, but there are also images of Scarlett Dark, O'Lan Jones, Jesse Shepard, Sam Rogers (Shepard's father) and Jessica Lange. The photographs are in the order in which Dark arranged them, and each has a unique identifying number (001-178) assigned by the archivist. In addition to the numbered photographs, there are over 250 snapshots taken by Dark. Many of these are duplicates of the numbered photographs, but there are several unique ones including shots of Shepard on the set of All the Pretty Horses with Matt Damon, photos from Jesse Shepard's wedding, and more photos of Shepard and of Dark.
  - 001 New York, Just before the Shepards were married. [3 photos], 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 002 Meanwhile in New York O-Lan had her baby (Jesse). [2 photos], 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 003 Sam reading "Music of the Spheres", undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 004 [Sam and O-Lan], 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 005 The Shepards in Fairfax, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 006 The Shepard's first visit from England. Fairfax, Calif., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 007 O-Lan, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 008 Jesse Shepard. Fairfax, Calif. [2 photos], 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 009 O-Lan, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 010 Scarlett outside our photo gallery, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 011 Meanwhile…Sam and Jesse in London England, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 012 Sam and Jesse on their way cross country to see us in Calif. Black Hills, South Dakota, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 013 Scarlett and "the girls." Civic Center San Raphael, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 014 That Summer Scarlett and I were married at the Civic Center in San Raphael, CA, September 18, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 015 O-Lan, England, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 016 Nova Scotia. Sam's new house, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 017 Sam and his yellow jeep on the beach which was part of his property, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 018 Sam, Jesse and Johnny, Nova Scotia, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 019 The Summer dismantling the side porch. Sam on Porch, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 020 Sam and Johnny, Nova Scotia, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 021 The family on the side porch, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 022 Sam, Scarlett, Johnny, Olan, Jesse, Kristy, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 023 [Sam and Johnny on porch], 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 024 John and Sam after the fall of the side porch, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 025 O-Lan, Jesse, Sam, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 026 Sam [with rifle] Nova Scotia, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 027 Sam on his old jeep, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 028 Sam, Sam's trick, Sam's baseball hat, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 029 Sam, Nova Scotia, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 030 Jesse's fifth birthday, Corte Madera, Calif., May 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 031 Sam at his old high school, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 032 Lincoln School, Sam's elementary school in South Pasadena. Sam and Jesse, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 033 Ranch house were Johnny and Sam and family all lived. Mill Valley, Calif, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 034 John and Sam [on horses], 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 035 O-Lan and Sam, Mill Valley, Calif. Movie still., 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 036 An Irish wolfhound [Molly], Jesse Shepard, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 037 Sam, Mill Valley Calif., 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 038 Sam and Jesse [in barn] around the time Sam was writing "Curse of the Starving Class", 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 039 Jesse at the shopping center, Calif., 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 040 Sam, Mill Valley, Calif., undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 041 The Family, Mill Valley, CA, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 042 Sam and Shelly Schoenberg, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 043 The Shepards in front of Sam's old truck, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 044 John and Sam and the great trip to Hollywood [Sam driving truck], 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 045 Scarlett and her two daughters in the kitchen, Calif, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 046 The Shepards, Calif, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 047 Sam with Jesse in another crazy outfit, Calif, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 048 Scarlett and John, Calif, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 049 Sam and Scarlett at home, Calif, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 050 Sam, Arizona, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 051 John in the study, Calif, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 052 Sam, Sonoma, Calif, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 053 Sam and O-Lan in the living room, Calif [2 photos], 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 054 [Sam building side patio with Jesse], Calif, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 055 [Sam with tiller], 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 056 Jesse and Sam in the living room, Calif, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 057 The Shepard/Dark house on Evergreen Ave, Mill Valley, CA, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 058 Picture of family drawn by O-Lan, Mill Valley, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 059 Sam and Scarlett, Calif [2 photos], December 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 060 Sam and Scarlett, Calif [2 photos], December 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 061 Sam helping Scarlett to stand and walk alone, Calif, December 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 062 Jesse and Sam [2 photos], 1973, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 063 Sam and O-Lan, Calif, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 064 Sam Sr. and Son, New Mexico and California [2 photos], 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 065 Sam Sr. in front of his homemade beer-top curtain, New Mex, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 066 [Sam in San Marcos, Tex on set of Raggedy Man], undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 067 San Marcos, Texas [Sam on set], 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 068 Sam and his attitude, Texas, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 069 Sam in Maxwell, Texas, for the extreme close up, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 070 [Photos of Sam for magazine interview re: The Right Stuff], Santa Fe [2 photos], 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 071 [Sam, Santa Fe] [2 photos], 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 072 Sam, Santa Fe, NM, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 073 Sam, NM, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 074 Santa Fe, NM [2 photos], 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 075 Sam, NM, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 076 Jessica and Sam on location, Waterloo, Iowa [3 photos], 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 077 Sam and Jessica, Santa Fe, NM, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 078 Jesse and Sam; Jesse [2 photos], 1973, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 079 Jessica and Sam, Santa Fe, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 080 Jessica and Sam, NM, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 081 Jesse and Sam, 1983, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 082 Sam, [Santa Fe], 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 083 Jessica, [Santa Fe], 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 084 Sam, Jessica and Shura [2 photos], 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 085 Jesse and Sam [NM], 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 086 Sam and Jesse, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 087 [Sam writing], Calif, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 088 [Sam in bed], Calif, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 089 Sam, Calif, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 090 Sam and Jesse, New Mexico, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 091 Sam Sr., Santa Fe, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 092 Sam Rogers, Sr., 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 093 Sam, Santa Rosa Calif [2 photos], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 094 Ranch house, Santa Rosa, Calif, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 095 Sam, Santa Rosa Calif [2 photos], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 096 Sam, Santa Fe New Mexico, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 097 Sam Sr. and Sam, New Mexico, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 098 Johnny and Sam [with truck and dog], 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 100 Johnny, NM, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 101 Sam and Johnny, NM [3 photos], 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 102 Jesse and Sam, Calif, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 103 Jesse and Sam, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 104 Sam and Jesse [shooting pistol][2 photos], 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 105 Dennis, Sam, Santa Rosa, Cali, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 106 [Sam with guitar], Calif, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 107 [Sam and dog], 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 108 Johnny [on motorcycle]. Mill Valley, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 109 Sam, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 110 Sam [2 photos], 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 111 Sam and Jesse in restaurant [2 photos], 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 112 Sam and Jesse in restaurant [2 photos], 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 113 Sam, VA, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 114 Sam's house, VA, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 115 Sam, Jesse and Johnny, VA, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 116 Sam and John, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 117 Sam and Jesse, VA, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 118 Sam on set, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 119 Sam, NM, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 120 Sam and Johnny [2 photos], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 121 Sam, Jesse, and Johnny, Calif [2 photos], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 122 Jesse and Sam, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 123 Jesse and Sam, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 124 Sam and Jesse [2 photos], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 125 Sam on the telephone, Calif, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 126 Sam and Jesse looking at photos, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 127 Sam and Jesse with Jesse's sculptures, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 128 Sam and Jesse, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 129 Sam and Scarlett [2 photos], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 130 Bill Hart, Johnny, Sam, Calif, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 131 Sam, Calif, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 132 Sam and John with their dads [2 photos], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 133 Johnny and Sam, Nova Scotia, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 134 Sam and John, Nova Scotia, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 135 John and Sam [with fake noses]. Mill Valley, CA, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 136 Sam and Johnny, Calif, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 137 Sam and John, Texas, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 138 Johnny and Sam, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 139 Sam and Johnny, Arizona, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 140 Sam and Johnny, Mill Valley, Calif, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 141 Sam and Johnny, Coalinga, CA, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 142 Johnny and Sam, Mill Valley [detail of photo 130 – different date given], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 143 Johnny and Sam, Los Angeles, Calif [2 photos], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 144 Sam and Johnny, San Luis Obispo, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 145 San and Johnny, New Mexico [2 photos], 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 146 Johnny and Sam, Santa Rosa, Calif, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 147 Johnny and Sam [shooting pistol], Santa Rosa, Calif, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 148 Johnny and Sam, Santa Rosa, Calif, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 149 Sam and Johnny, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 150 Sam and Johnny, Mill Valley, Calif, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 151 Johnny and Sam, Virginia, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 152 Sam and Johnny, Virginia, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 153 Johnny and Sam, Noodle, Texas, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 154 Sam and Johnny, Santa Rosa, California, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 155 Johnny and Sam, Deming, New Mexico, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 156 Sam at 57, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 157 Sam, Johnny, and Scarlett [2 photos], undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 158 Sam, Calif [2 photos], 2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 159 Sam and Johnny, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 160 Sam at 63 at Jesse's wedding, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 161 Sam and Hanna at Jesse's wedding [2 photos], 2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 162 Sam and Jesse at Jesse's wedding, Calif, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 163 Sam and Jesse toasting at Jesse's wedding, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 164 Johnny and Sam, New York, NY, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 165 Sam, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 166 John and Sam, Santa Fe, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 167 Sam and John, Deming, NM, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 168 Sam and Scarlett, Deming, NM, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 169 Sam, John and dog, [Seming, NM], 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 170 Sam, Palomas, Mexico, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 171 Sam drinking coffee, [Mexico], 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 172 Sam, [Mexico], 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 173 Sam, [Mexico], 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 174 Sam in park, [Mexico], 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 175 Sam smoking cigar, [Mexico], 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 176 Sam walking, [Mexico], 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 177 Sam with truck, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 178 Sam on set [digital print; annotated & inscribed by Dark], 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Snapshots
    - Photos of Sam Shepard [many are duplicates of photos in box 5] (60 snapshots) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - On set of All the Pretty Horses with Matt Damon (2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Jesse Shepard's wedding (18) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Filming Shepard & Dark with Treva Wurmfeld (29) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Photos of Johnny Dark (54) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Family and friends (40) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified women (31) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Street scenes and landscapes (42) (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Audio Material, 1976-2002, undated
  Series IV: Audio Material contains 28 tapes of varying audio quality. Most of the tapes feature conversations between Shepard and Dark - some recorded in person, some over the telephone. The tapes from the 1970s and 1980s form the basis of Dark's typescript, Dialogues, in Series II. All of the cassettes have been digitized, and there are listening copies available. Archives staff have provided summaries of many, but not all, of the digitized tapes.
  - Tape 001 Side A: "Sam and John" Side B: "Jazz" [Note: no summary available] (Box 7)
  - Tape 002 Side A: "John and SamSam Shepard discusses various developments in the process of writing a play, such as names, clothing, lifestyle." Side B: "Darin and Mercer" (Box 7)
    Description
    Johnny talks about an old girlfriend named Evelyn and the first time they met. He gives a description of her physical appearance and how they "made out" in a car. There are also various other things that are hard to hear or understand because of the low volume.
  - Tape 003 Side A: "Sam and Johnny, May 7 1983" Sam and Johnny play guitar and sing songs and discuss various things, much of which is hard to understand because of the low volume. Side B: blank (Box 7)
  - Tape 004 Side A: "Sam and John" Side B: "Women Swing" (Box 7)
    Side A: On this side of the tape, Sam and Johnny play guitar and sing songs. They discuss different places they have lived, how Los Angeles started out as a hacienda, how to become a "man with a mission", how Sam's first play had old men in it and how his plays have young men who turn old. They also discuss the racial tensions with Jazz music in the 1940's and how they should make movies about it.
    Side B: Johnny discusses the contents of a letter he received from a girlfriend about how she is not in love with him. Johnny goes on to talk about the break up and some of his past relationships.
  - Tape 005 Side A: "Johnny and Sam, Santa Fe July 1983" Side B: unlabeled (Box 7)
    Side A: Sam and Johnny talk about rugged individualism, luck and circumstances as factors of success and achievement. They try to define rugged and come to the conclusion that it is a false concept. They also briefly talk about the movie "The Right Stuff" and various things about it.
    Side B: Sam and Johnny continue their discussion on rugged individualism, what the rugged individual would posses as far as material things, knowing whether you have ruggedness or not and having the "right stuff". They also make a list of people throughout history who have had the "right stuff". Sam also discusses filming The Right Stuff and how hard it was to film yet everyone worked as a team and how writing letters are a more personal way of communication.
  - Tape 006 Side A: "Johnny and Sam, Santa Fe July 1983" Side B: unlabeled (Box 7)
    Side A: This is a continuation from the previous tape. They continue to make of list of people in history who have and did not have the "right stuff". Sam also talks more about filming The Right Stuff.
    Side B: Sam and Johnny discuss writing the epilogue, Chuck Yeager's abilities, how Sam is receiving scripts and conditioning for polo.
  - Tape 007 Side A: "Sam and John 5/5/94 Drinking and Drugs" Side B: "Me [Dark] and Scarlett talking about self remembering 5/13", May 5, 1994, May 13, [1994] (Box 7)
    Side A: A phone conversation between Sam and Johnny about several adventures in drinking and getting "smashed". Their conversation eventually turns to drug experiences, addictions and what affects smoking grass had on them. They also discuss what books they are currently reading at the moment. Johnny also talks about his time living in Tangiers and Valencia and moving back to Connecticut. He relates the story about how he met Scarlett.
    Side B: Johnny and Scarlett discuss between themselves about the difference between self-observation and self-remembering and what it means.
  - Tape 008 Side A: "Scarlett" Side B: "Lisa Vale fan club" (Box 7)
    Side A: Scarlett discusses with Johnny some of her favorite things such as her favorite dish, animal, weather, locale and winter sports. Johnny reads Scarlett some stories, using voices as he reads. (Note: Tape has some speed variation issues)
    Side B: Sam and Johnny jokingly discuss creating The Lisa Vale Fan Club and have fun writing a drunken letter to her
  - Tape 009 Side A: "Sam and John reminiscing 4/12/94" Side B: unlabeled, April 12, 1994 (Box 7)
    Side A: Sam and Johnny have a phone conversation and talk about a friend they both had conversations with who is writing a book. They discuss previous and current relationships problems, past experiences and memories. The conversation eventually focuses on Sam's efforts to learn to play the piano.